HUANG Huajian(黄华健)

Gender: Male E-mail: hhuangbq@connect.ust.hk; hhuangbq@connect.ust.hk; huajian.huang99@gmail.com

Homepage: https://huajianup.github.io/

I am pursuing PhD in the Hong Kong University of Science and Technology, advised by Professor Sai-Kit Yeung. I have passion in SLAM (simultaneous localization and mapping) and reconstruction. Recently I am exploring omnidirectional vision for various tasks of computer vision and robotics.

Research topic

Computer vision, SLAM, 3D reconstruction

Education

09/2014 -- 06/2018 **Sun Yat-sen University (B.Eng)**

Major in Communication Engineering

08/2019 -- The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (PhD)

Major in Computer Science and Engineering

Publications

2022

360VO: Visual Odometry Using A Single 360 Camera

Huajian, Huang and Sai-Kit Yeung

In Proc. of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

SiamX: An Efficient Long-term Tracker Using Cross-level Feature Correlation and Adaptive Tracking Scheme

Huajian, Huang and Sai-Kit Yeung

In Proc. of the IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

360ST-Mapping: An Online Semantics-Guided topological mapping Module for Omnidirectional Visual SLAM

Hongji Liu, Huajian Huang, Sai-Kit Yeung and Ming Liu

In Proc. of International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

2020 **Dual-SLAM: A framework for robust single camera navigation**

Huajian Huang, Wen-Yan Lin, Siying Liu, Dong Zhang and Sai-Kit Yeung

Project page: https://huajianup.github.io/research/Dual_SLAM/

Code: https://github.com/HuajianUP/Dual_SLAM

In Proc. of International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS)

Intern

2017 -- 2018 Research Assistant

ADSC/Illinois at Singapore Pte Ltd

Related Experience

2014 -- 2017 won the university scholarship for three years in succession

12/2016 -- 06/2017 Information Science & Technology Developing Center for SYSU Students

• Vice Minister of Electronic Design Club

08/2016 -- 05/2017 "Challenge Cup" Undergraduate Curricular Academic Science and Technology Works

 design and develop a smart cushion system that can determine sitting posture and record time to help people keep healthy

won the second prize in the 14th Challenge Cup

11/2015 -- 08/2016 The 11th NXP Cup National University Students Intelligent Car Race

Project leader in SYSU

03/2015 -- 10/2015 China Robotics Competition & RoboCup

responsible for embedded development.

won the first prize